Finding Aid for Hazel Harper Whittaker Vandenberg papers, 1928-1948
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Hazel Harper Whittaker Vandenberg papers 1928-1948
Vandenberg, Hazel Whittaker, 1882-1950.
2 linear ft. (12 v. and ca. 225 items) and 2 oversize volumes
86163 AC Aa 2
Wife of Senator Arthur Vandenberg, diaries containing description of social activities and daily political life in Washington; included as part of diaries are newspaper clippings, photographs, programs, and other personal miscellanea; also scrapbooks, 1928-1950.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received from Arthur Vandenberg, Jr. and Elizabeth Vandenberg Sands (Donor No. 5425 and 4451 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
Hazel Hart Whittaker was the second wife of Republican Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg of Michigan of Michigan. She was a 1906 graduate of the University of Michigan, where she first met Vandenberg. Whitaker worked as a newspaper reporter, including a spell as a woman's page writer for the Chicago Tribune. She married Vandenberg in 1918 and together they raised three children, Arthur jr., Barbara, and Elizabeth, from his previous marriage. Hazel Vandenberg died June 10, 1950
The papers,1928-1950, of Hazel Vandenberg, wife of Michigan Republican Senator, Arthur H. Vandenberg; include diaries with descriptions of social activities and daily political life in Washington; included as part of diaries are newspaper clippings, photographs, programs, and other personal miscellanea; also scrapbooks,1928-1950.
Subjects:
Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1953.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Washington (D.C.); Women--Washington (D.C.); Legislators' spouses--Washington (D.C.); Scrapbooks.; Vandenberg, Hazel Whittaker, 1882-1950.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Diaries, 1928-1948
  - Diary, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Diary, September 1929-July 1930 (Box 1)
  - Diary, Fall, 1930-July 1932 (Box 1)
  - Diary, December 1932-June 1934 (Box 1)
  - Diary, December 1934-June 1936 (Box 1)
  - Diary, January 1937-June 1938 (Box 1)
  - Diary, November 1936-June 1939 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1939-194o (Box 2)
  - Diary, December 1940-June 1942 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1942-1946 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1945 concerning San Francisco Conference (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook of articles written for the Grand Rapids Women's City Club Bulletin, 1934-1950, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1940, Outsize volume (Volume 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1949, Outsize volume (Volume 2)